all right to you project raising in part
to brainstorming on brainstorming we're
we're talking about creating what are we
talking about brainstorming on
brainstorming continuing from last last
time worry I can't recap what I just
watched yesterday but it was an amazing
conversation it us and Kyra was that it
was Kara the only other no units to
right there bola right yonis wasn't a
picture on the screen for part of it so
it's never just about that right yeah so
who would like to get us started or
start off the conversation brainstorming
I'm brainstorming I mean we could we
could pick up where we left off kind of
um I do have maybe this is a good place
to start I do have a question um you
mentioned in p.m. to me and also I
noticed in a thread this week somewhere
about how you are seeing a lot of motion
towards I mean stuff starting to happen
and so could you talk about that a
little more because I'm at has plugged
in to all these these video chats as you
are and and I'm really that really
caught my attention I also literally
made like my worlds happen in flick I
all the conversations I'm part of are
becoming the same meta conversation like
we're meeting on Fridays and Saturdays
and talking about the meta project for
projects meeting people where they are
and having those those conversations and
it's it's moving forward like we're
talking about creating the calendar and
creating a schedule or in creating like
what's the little thing you can create
it's gonna facilitate that and then I
know once we have that it's gonna you
know snowball and the next thing will be
there but more what I was talking about
I don't is especially not us because
Bentley like saw the vision right like I
think he already had the vision of like
what a tech cooperative could be Adriel
also you know to a certain point but
there were three conversations one with
my brother a drill and one with Heather
one with David where I could see they
saw the vision like my brother I've been
talking about this for years and he
doesn't quite see my vision but I think
he with game B's is more like
yes the together piece of tech is is
powerful like I feel like he got it more
than I had felt he got it in the past
and that's just my interpretation of it
but with Heather and David both who are
both very non tech necessarily more of
the other side of like the personal
development they both like got it in
this way in two different conversations
where I was like yes like the scheduler
is the thing like that brings us
together for like the infrastructure for
creating the community and the
brainstorming for brainstorming and
being able to create something from the
ground up is game B and there's like
this point where people get that like
it's it's not just technology it's
connection it's it's giving people
something they don't have right now that
is a natural attractor that is the next
step and so I can just see that coming
together it's already in me but it's
like happening in in the world outside
so that's just where it was a few weeks
what I've been experiencing
yeah I've seen people make comments like
well I would get more involved and you
know this includes myself as well I
would I would get warned volved in the
in the video chats if I knew more or if
I had more time or you know there's um
so I think the schedule water idea is
really good yeah I feel like I should
have rewatched our woman who two weeks
ago like right before this because it
was at the end of what we were talking
about we were it's kind of talking about
it wasn't the scheduler exactly it was
kind of more of the like talent exchange
there was something there or it was kind
of like I'm gonna continue on with this
conversation and then that way because
of the Friday one and they're all that's
that's fine
it's how this wants to put my head at
the moment yeah I buy really crazier
metaponto right like I see a lot of
stuff happening that is kind of aligned
with the game beat stuff but it kind of
lies outside of it
and
a lot of platforms being developed
you know the p2p space and you know in
vieta I think it's called just different
platforms and I'm wondering what people
think of like piggybacking on some of
this stuff or bringing it in or or
instead of trying to like you know
reinvent the wheel with everything if
there is a way to actually surface all
of this stuff as well and you know in
addition to surfacing our projects but
surfacing these outside things as well
and to determine whether or not they
would be useful yeah I think our
philosophy should be and I think Julie
and magically agree is we're gonna use
whatever is out there right now as long
as it doesn't have as long as it doesn't
drag us too much towards game a which
you know Facebook and Twitter are a bit
like change your brain and to game a so
it might be good at some point to do
that but yeah reuse as much that's out
there and it's my other groups and also
be kind of a central clearinghouse on on
what tools are out there and how they
can be used in projects most efficiently
right yeah I see that as a real boost
you know potential boost because there
is a lot of stuff going on out there and
I'm always amazed to discover something
and realize that you know it's not
really game a it's it's pretty aligned
with what's going on in the game B but
they're separate they're you know there
hasn't been a connection made yeah and I
was I was to that point I was playing
with bubble Daiya and it's more
expensive that I would like but you can
do one kind of free app prototype per
account and it lets you drag and drop
forms and elements but also has a work
so after they submit the data here it
can go into here and it can connect out
to to Google or to therapy or stuff like
that so I think that'll be a good tool
for if we have an idea to quickly
prototype it and get feedback using
mostly the free account but only one
person the free account is one person
for one app and it doesn't have all the
automation but we could someone could
take the initiative and prototype it and
we could play with it and see if it
works and then you know then move it off
on our own platform unless someone wants
to pay for the bubble account
I was looking at yesterday was it I said
up to 50 people like what it'd be 50 of
us collaborating on Caribbean or 50
people like with accounts that are
signing up to be part of the scheduler
like is it I actually didn't see the 50
person thing so maybe that's of the
users of the app you're creating I know
you can only have one app designer so I
may not have seen that limitation so I
think I'm what we're doing for the meta
project right we're meeting on the
Fridays and figuring out what
facilitates projects and what is gonna
draw those people in that's where those
people but we're also the people who are
don't have projects and want to work on
projects right now kind of what
brainstorming brainstorming is is how to
include everyone does it have the
project and I think that in and of
itself is like that is the scheduler
right it's like well you just come and
you need to know which conversation to
be a part of and what your time zone is
but to have that conversation with what
do they want right because we can think
what they want and put it into it but to
actually say that was kind of what I did
on the game beast face yesterday it was
like wow we're having these
conversations I'm really enjoying it
I seem to be okay getting into
conversations a little too much but what
is it that stops them and the answers
that I thought of and were there were
like time zone and scheduling like
knew it was happening I would probably
come on board and then there's the other
ones of like well I'm not comfortable
yet I don't feel you know I I don't want
to be seen in that space or I'm just
watcher and we've had those
conversations Buffy he introverts and
how do we make them feel safe and it's
about having those conversations with
them and having it be a space that isn't
live on YouTube and I want to zoom there
is that and then creating a culture of
being able to make mistakes both
technical and personal you know to be
able to like lose your and still
have Redemption I think it'd be nice to
to on you know so say you say you
discover a project and you're interested
in it but you don't really have the
skills or expertise to contribute to it
but you would like to stay with it and
maybe there'd be a way to have like a
breakout something or other where you
can actually talk to the people involved
and learn more and you know either
determine whether that's a good fit for
you in the future or you know what you
need to do to get up to speed to become
a participant in that project I think
that's so important
like but it's getting those people
involves getting the people under
projects involved to say what would you
need from a group of people what would
get them up to speed what are you
comfortable sharing and not hurting and
then for the people like who want to get
involved what do you feel comfortable in
right you don't want to be handed here
here's our marking account go for it
right like you want to know that you
have the skill to be able to do a thing
and to get it right
does it make sense to you right is it
all in technical jargon because that's
one of the reasons I haven't felt that I
can get involved in the peer-to-peer or
in spiral or those things is it's for
tech people it's for like even when they
say it's not it's like uh it's still you
need to have a certain amount of that
information to be able to be involved in
oh and I think there needs to be a space
for everyone a space for that doesn't
make sense to me make it make sense to
me
right if you're interested in it there
should be a way to disseminate the
information that gets you up to speed
without right the CEO needing to sit
down with you and have a conversation
and walk you through it right like it
can't be one on one time and it can't be
I think if you know like right now it
could be for our projects because
they're not very far but when you have
30 people contacting you every week
there needs to be a process for yeah
coming part of our live conversation and
read this white page before then great
well I think it's important you know we
all have limited capacities both
cognitively you know time resources but
what what I would hope is going to start
happening here is just this a huge
balloon expansion of opportunities and
new ideas and you know right now in game
a type dynamics you know it's like okay
well it looks like I'm interested in
this sort of thing so now I'm gonna go
to school for four years you know major
in computer science or whatever and all
of that might not be necessary actually
to contribute to something that you've
determined through this process we're
talking about that you're passionate
about but there's really no other
recourse at this point to actually get
involved in this so um you know maybe
and I don't know maybe there isn't but
maybe there's another way to approach
this kind of thing yeah I think we
talked about it last time it's like just
showing up as you is enough if the
platform is there to facilitate that and
the culture is there to allow that right
that people can show up and make
mistakes and that there's a way to
kindly be like if there is a circle of
expertise that you have to be a part of
like a technology you know you have to
we're coding this you need to know what
we're talking about in order to be part
of this conversation that it's not done
hopefully in a shame creating way right
like you're not deficient because you
can't be part of that conversation you
just can't be part of that conversation
and there's other ways for you to be
able to participate
right you know an ability to really
determine you know what I'm just this
isn't my thing you know I'm or there's
too much to learn you know it's it's
like you know you can't just say oh I'm
interested in this blockchain project
and now I mean I start coding next week
it doesn't work that way
but you know there there is a path
without having to go get a computer
science degree to I mean people already
do that but there's it's not easy it's
it's hard and the whole failure thing
constantly comes in you know it's like
well I'm not gonna even try that because
I'm afraid of failure so yeah okay one
of the things that is coming up is like
a makes things more complicated we don't
need more a more complicated platform to
create but a volunteer platform it
actually is dealing with like actual
not-for-profits and social enterprises
and it just a job description type one
but also with the UM backend to actually
help facilitate that process right if
you have an event you need caterers at
like whatever the actual job is I know
they kind of already exist fall into
your platforms but not really like
whatever I've looked at them they're not
they don't meet the person where they
are and they don't they're not so there
and they don't have enough all into your
people on there like they don't have
enough organizations that need
volunteers on there if it wasn't I as
the Cancer Foundation person have to put
arms on there but anyone can put it on
there and say hey I know that we have
you know we're doing a marathon this
weekend and we need people to hand out
juice and have it be more simple to
volunteer to get people to get because
that brings the people and then have
ways that people can just be part of
conversations but that seems a lot of
convoluted to get the people from the
scheduler and
so what's the kind of next step to move
forward on the ability to brainstorm is
it yeah I don't know I'm just thinking
through that oh I think you think
something earlier and I don't know if
you got this a well yeah next I think
one thing that I was hoping we could
touch on is this time is what are we
gonna do next you know do we break out a
another separate video chat around the
subject and zoom into it more or how to
approach that
well maybe we kind of summarize what
lessons we learned or first so we talked
about that it would be good if it was a
place it may be focusing it more on a
space where people can bring problems
and then work with a group to do
solutions so do we need I mean I think
just scheduling a recurring video call
where people can just throw problems and
have everyone brainstorm solutions I
think would be a good next step and then
I don't know if we want this to also
include the whole I mean is our whole
discussion about
[Music]
about volunteers and project you know a
database list of projects and tools that
all part of the brainstorming space or
is that just part of together tech as a
detective space or sort of a lot I think
I like the idea of like a zoom call or
conference type situation where people
can bring problems to me we can kind of
source solutions how do we want to like
brands that like is it hey I'm having
trouble with my kid she's not sleeping
through the night or is it getting be
problems right like I need to know how
to feed myself so that I can concentrate
on this because those are similar and
yet not quite or are they no I have
together tech for figuring out a
schedule or how do we move forward with
it like it's an actual game be projects
is it game be people with problems or is
it a bigger circle of just life because
everything's game B I would like to see
it be more yeah I don't know how to say
it but not so much like individual
issues for like individual people but
more like you know people that are
finding how they want to where they want
to provide value to the universe and
they've identified a problem that
they're passionate about and then so
like what's the next step yeah or they
have more problem to solve right let's
see if we can help you get a step
forward
yeah right or just even also if there
isn't any of that then the next thing
would be you know here's a project I'm
working on here's a problem I hit in it
let's just all which is kind of like the
continuation of the project raising
thing but that's another option second
object mm-hmm kind of my groups it's or
the coopertition yeah like it's like
they're actually hey maybe you better to
keep that separate over there but yeah
yeah I think I think it was last
Saturday Jonas brought up
talking about scale of you know problems
so one one potential function of
brainstorming our brainstorming could be
bringing your problem to the group and
kind of brainstorming over you know
what's the scale this problem and what
are the resources that potentially we
can surface to help with this problem
and is that doable you know is it's a
scale like we're gonna solve climate
change well no we're not you know we
don't we don't have the resources and
the people available here to do that you
know that's an extreme example but kind
of determined you know the scale of the
potential scale of a project that you're
concerned about what resources might be
available to start working on that you
know who's interested in it and all that
I don't know how to facilitate that okay
wait so yeah I'd say that one more time
okay so you know so you know you bring a
you bring a problem to the group that
you're passionate about and you know
you're not there might be some question
as to the scale of the problem as far as
you know the problem solution space is
is there a solution that is potentially
possible given the resources the people
the interest that we can surface in this
group to help you along to the next step
of of solving that problem because it's
not always clear you know it's that's
why I've brought up also you know all
the platforms and the projects that are
happening out there so it's not always
clear of that that problem
is solvable at at the scale we're
working at here
well I yeah I think though if if we just
simply have like a repeating meeting
where anyone can join pitch their
problem and then then that would be part
of the discussion is how could they take
the next step towards it or I don't know
that we would ever say it's too big to
be for us to contribute to it as
individuals nor that individual but that
could definitely be part of the
discussion but I wouldn't I don't I
can't think of it I don't think there's
a need for to put any formality around
that except maybe to have a list of when
someone brings a problem what are the
topics like funding resources existing
technology that could be reused existing
projects that solve the same thing that
we could use as a guide when we're going
through the discussion but I don't think
it needs being more formal than that
okay now that that makes sense I mean
just going through that process I mean
yeah you would be able to figure that
out yeah it's really the the kind of the
knowledge the skills and the experience
of the other people that's the that's
the value just and just to have someone
to bounce your ideas off of so you're
not in this little bitty echo chamber
right yeah I think that's a huge value
to anyone but maybe back to Julie's
question how do we want to kind of brand
this or maybe we could construct the
name and then a one or two sentence
description so that people will know
what to expect or be attracted to doing
that if they want
brainstorm eon brainstorming is a kind
of awkward yes yes it is yeah I mean
something like yeah I don't know I guess
the long way of saying it talk to us
I've found a problem in the world that
I'm passionate about help me figure out
what's next right about what's next yeah
I just ordered the patch that says that
yeah but I I think we do need this yeah
or maybe something like first steps mmm
because they're there they're coming or
maybe even we need to open up further
and say well I don't know okay I was
gonna say I don't know what I'm
passionate about or what I want to do
but really for those people they need to
watch the project raising calls and they
can get interested in an existing
project right so that's not this space
this space is yeah I mean yeah it's kind
of like does this speak to anybody when
there's a current event that happens
like the coronavirus or that Iran
America thing right now game a is to
just like we don't know what's even
going on we don't and there's sense
making projects but there isn't a space
to actually go and talk about it to talk
about your fears to talk about like
that's not happiness I don't know if we
can do anything about the corona virus
but to be able to just have a space to
go and chat means that those things
could come up but I think he lights a
completely different project but there's
something about that where it's just
like the inkling of I care about this
thing it's in my emotions how do we
start having a conversation I feel like
that brings more people to the table
because that's my worry is that it's
just going to be the three or four of us
solving problems for people
right like how do we bring people to the
table to be part of that conversation
have it be a zoom call with you know
like 50 people we are broken out into
groups and this is the problem for the
week right huh that's interesting the
problems mark yeah I think that
definitely has an overlap with the idea
yeah and it can be very game be specific
it could be racism and game be right
like something that's like brought up
emotion that week and I think people
want to talk about I think valuable and
and maybe this is a bit reductionist but
you know you bring in a problem and you
kind of talk about it and 0 into more
first principles and determine you know
what kind of problem what kind of
solution really are we talking about you
know we're not we're not going to solve
this problem in in the box that exists
in we have to drill down deeper and then
for me what a useful framework for me is
thinking in terms of Gabey and
transition be so you know is this a is
this a solution at the level that the
problem is to be solved that that is
more of a transition problem that we can
start working on right now for example
okay maybe blockchain isn't ideal maybe
it's got a whole host of problems but
perhaps it's a transitional solution
that'll work and we can get started on
it so you know kind of kind of
determining the space in that way yeah
yeah so I'm thinking of another so
Jubilee talked about there's a there's a
topical issue coming up that we may
people may want to discuss and then
problem-solve around it I think that
there's also the I already have a
passion like I discussed so I mentioned
that but I don't know where to start
know if anyone's actually gonna be in
that space I wouldn't be surprised if
everyone has a passion about something
and before they get to the call they'll
have started on a solution path and then
there are a project right I don't know
if you can see it that way or not but
also there's the space of I want to be a
value to the world so maybe it's just a
brainstorming where a person comes in
and says I want to provide more value to
the world let's brainstorm how I can do
that and then in that discussion we talk
about what are you passionate about
about food about poverty about about
decision-making about you know and then
we kind of help them through the process
so maybe it's more focused on an
individual that wants to provide more
value because that sounds like that's
even more kind of what I think this
started out as Edward II can correct me
no I think you're right that's correct
there's a something here for like a
let's say a two hour conference for
people anyone in the Gabey space or
pupae notes the bigger community for
that come and figure out what you're
passionate about maybe we will find
poverty food you know a being like
clumps of people and then coordinating
how we get those people together to
solve something right on their own time
without us necessarily facilitate that
like just see how it goes like see how
many people are interested in fine you
know stuff that they're passionate about
what is there everyone has their thing
the game be is about we ought to solve
this one first and my answer is right
all of them are it just not for you
like frenzies is currency by ours is
like the communication piece or the
scheduler like everyone has like their
own passion project but bringing people
together to brainstorm that right to say
hey this is the one thing I think I care
deeply about and then finding the other
people who care deeply about that I'm
starting the conversation of like how
can we support each other maybe
mastermind groups come out of it maybe
nothing comes out of it I don't yeah
like the title might be something I find
or start my passion project
to provide value to the world you know
in parentheses and this gosh something
else who said I lost it go ahead and
then that maybe it would just be as
simple as a zoom call that also has a
Google Doc of like hey did you are like
a spreadsheet did you what are the
common themes or what are the things
you're passionate about is it everything
right poverty climate change or is it
very niche I care about like poodles and
Arkansas like what is the what is your
thing and how do they kind of come
together and is there common themes
throughout it and then just presenting
that back to the community it's like hey
here's what we learned and how do you
guys want or guys around the same issue
people that are just available at the
same time it doesn't matter what your
passion project is like what yeah I
would caution against calling at a
conference until we know that there's a
large enough group of people for that
I'd almost say let's just call it a zoom
call and if there's many people then you
break up in groups but yeah I would
really like to see that level although I
think in game B everyone everyone
already knows not everyone most people
know their passion so I don't think
we'll have a huge volume on this
brainstorming piece yeah yeah that's
that's what I'm thinking too it's like
it's more at the levels start your
passion I mean if you're not sure of
your passion maybe you just hang out and
watch and determine that that if we
start down at that level it's I think
start your passion is great because I
think I think people will Intuit that if
they don't know what their passion is
that starting would include finding it
so maybe that's kind of assumed mmm
y'all can correct me if you think that
that's too far two steps so I think we
could count like start my passion or
start my value and and it'll still draw
the people that are like well I want to
do something in this space but I don't
know where to start
right Wow because we want the people who
know what their passion is they know
it's technology they don't say they know
it we don't even like they know the
piece but also people have no idea who
are like I'm just here because I want
game B I don't know where I fit but once
other people start talking about it I
think you start resonating oh yes I want
to solve that problem and that problem
that problem yeah and they might just be
part of a conversation on all the
different things or they might focus in
on one of them and we could certainly
explain that this is all sort of people
that have no idea what their passion is
just to clarify but yeah I think the
name could just be start my passion or
something yeah start my passion and then
I guess the next steps for this might be
just to put a post and see if there's
anyone interested in doing that and if
so we can either reuse this time slot as
part of one of the project periodic
project raisings could be a start my
passion episode or we could break it
apart I don't know how y'all feel about
that I feel like for this in particular
we wanted to be a zoom call we want it
to not be live on YouTube because
otherwise it will just be there right
you're right you're right
and it'll be record and you could even
like if I like if a person's talking it
we don't have time to do this maybe but
you could edit out just one person's
passion discussion and brainstorming if
we wanted to but yeah I agree especially
if it's more focused like if we're
talking about my passion right now and
then we're brainstorming it and then a
drills right that's much easier to cut
out then like yeah mines intermix
throughout all of it and that's how it's
gonna be is people gonna bring you're
right but there's no like it's like they
have like a two-hour conversation on
like Joe Rogan or rebel wisdom and then
they also have like the five minute ten
minutes
snippets that they put out that are like
to kind of bring you back there that
could also be right that somewhat chunky
for like these are your project
and also yeah who we want it'll be great
for the person to have that to put it
out to game be right like they always
said are able to talk amazingly about
the thing that they're passionate about
food and then it's like to put that
piece out so people can watch it and
that also works with just taking the
time I'm talking at the 24 minute mark
and sharing from that point right yeah
sooo mning everyone's okay with it being
shared so it's still don't have to get
permission from everyone that really had
a substantial piece right right it's
like audio too but not on YouTube yeah
right Supercop also we probably want to
have like an actual zoom account which I
know there's enough out there in game B
but putting that out there to like who
has a zoom account they're willing to
use for a Saturday or Sunday morning cuz
this is also I feels like a thing we
want to do on the weekend
but I don't want to do too much on the
weekend like I don't want to have weekly
things in the weekend the weekends for
me and my kid I already have this one
blocked out um but doing it twice a
month or once a month on a Saturday
maybe right after this call like but
that's like a long maybe we do it
instead of this call we just don't have
the project raising that week and do it
on zoom yeah I might need to buy a zoom
account for my business so I guess I
need to look into that I mean for our
big a call as we do just we waited for
the 40 minutes to go and then we just
read click on it and go right back in
and it's Eric it's recording like when
Eric's there it's recording yeah you set
the meeting at 40 minutes then like
that's the limit for one person or
something then yeah yeah but I do it is
a like a break like it's like to get
right back into the conversation
sometimes it happens at the perfect time
actually but mostly it cuts people off
and here you know coming back in and Ari
looks like you need the intro and to re
get back into the conversation every
time which takes its own time out of the
40 minutes right mm-hmm oh and yeah the
basic plan should be fine hundred
participants 24 hours for
meaning duration let's go for a marathon
fight passion every I mean that is it my
dream is that people don't need to be
facilitated like here's the plan you
jump in on the hour and then break out
into passion projects and nobody needs
to facilitate that but no one's there
yet oh yeah yeah get a little bit of
guidance before because then it can be
breaking down into timeslot one zoom
account and it's like the food people
meet at 9:00 a.m. till till 10:00 and
there's a way to do soon as well I
believe we're even known people are in
breakout groups other people can come
and join and there's like a lobby and
you can go off and kind of I think Eric
was also talking about using five
different free zoom accounts and having
one be the lobby so you like when you're
done with yours you come back and form
new groups that was more for or that
type of conversation oh you can so at
the base account you can have other
people a sunny
oh the person must have appropriate okay
ignore me I know you can let other
people host and have other people do
that cuz Christian does it with it game
be cafe he had the host code he was he
gave it out because I had it at one
point oh and yeah you might need to have
an account but if you have it like I
mean - zoom account it's free it's like
the same URL that I can use you know
again but then if so like but that still
means I can host right you'd like a paid
account on someone else's if they need
me to because I mean how about account
not that I know how to get into it well
what the password it is but needs to
know these things yeah I mean that the
pricing isn't bad $15 a month gets you a
hundred participants meeting duration is
24 hours it's that's pretty good yeah
I'm guessing this
twenty-four hours of total meeting time
in the month yep paid zoom virgin you
have a 24 hour account you could have
had a persistence in yeah 24 hours
leading early fear about that yeah it
means that if you have the median it's
oh it can only go on for 24 hours and
you have to restart a new meeting that's
it there's people coming in and out then
it's never 24 hours anyway I mean I
believe that is that is there as my
remark we live in on that yeah I don't
think what's the difference between the
tears I'm just thinking from like a game
a pricing model and they weren't
perfectly marthy hit that limit that's a
good problem to have
well if you get to the next level you
get like 300 participants mm-hmm so it's
just the concurrent participants cuz
well there's several other features but
that's the important one custom branding
custom emails single sign-on energy
domains Oh vanity URL stuff like that oh
all like the sort of the be nice to have
enterprise stuff yeah yeah
come business side that was my business
model for cafe it was like we just have
zoom accounts 100 like $15 a month for
every hundred we have in the team at the
same time slot for good but as long as
you're open and transparent about that
it's like that's the level of
professionalism around we're using zoom
like that's totally fine we don't have
millions of dollars to put into new
video software to create why not use
what's already there and zoom works
pretty good you also just I mean it'd be
a little bit more complex and not
everyone's on Facebook but I think you
could have a group in Facebook and do a
meeting in there but I think that
requires that require more management I
mean I like the idea of having a
Facebook group where it's not just
Saturday mornings right but but it's
anyone can kind of say hey I want to I
have a problem I want a brain start at
this time period but I feel like first
we need the conference that's on a
conference like how much because if
there's four people interested starting
a Facebook group doesn't make sense if
there's four people interested in
starting a Facebook group and they're
gonna actively market it and get more
people on board awesome
that's where like if someone's passion
project is this passion project right
right it needs some energy behind it I
think a problem with for lying too much
on a Facebook group for something like
this though is the ability to search and
find what you're looking for just
horrible on Facebook and so that's
pretty important function for what we're
talking about here you know oh I heard
this and this will apply to what I'm
thinking about right now but where is it
yeah although if we're doing mostly
video we're gonna it's not searchable
either but yeah yeah is anyone aware of
any decent transcription software but
the auto Rio accounts that um I've been
transcribing stuff Anthony was and then
someone kind of chastised him for it not
I haven't seen him in the space since
then unfortunately hmm and if we upload
it to YouTube at some point I think
that's got the built in one right yep
yeah but that's not the same as the
transcription its searchable like yeah I
mean just just kind of a workaround I
mean like Bentley says video isn't
really searchable at this time but you
can create workarounds that hopefully
aren't too much work I think it's also
like having video and then having like a
Google Doc or something else where you
have to like actually pick what is the
most important and salient and type it
out and put it in there right like hey
we decided to create passion project
right and like here's the bullet points
it's not as great as AI doing it cuz
there's I don't want to take notes it's
not really within my brains capacity at
all but that is the level for app is we
do be doing that and then
is like the more people willing to take
notes and collect that information the
more information we have to be I'll do
that with like someone had done a is it
Rome a Rome account for this one or they
were yeah that's what I started you
started an effort look at me look at me
I think Randy was the one that was gonna
do the transcriptions I believe that
yeah I just haven't had time to dig into
it yet like like I would like to but I
mean it's amazing they're talking about
you know switching it over to a paid
model which you know if if it turns out
to be what it appears it's going to be I
would consider it worth it for myself
but yeah I just I mean it you know it
has to weigh links so basically you
don't have to organize things you know
think about you know what category this
falls into or what category that falls
into and create a you know a folder
structured data structure for those
things it just does it itself you know
you basically any any word or concept or
name or whatever you turn it into a link
and each link has its own page and then
you know you could it just pretty much
organizes itself so it's a really
amazing way to take notes and be
creative and integrate ideas together
but I just don't know enough about at
this point project to be it's figuring
out all these things cuz they need to
make money like they need to make money
but making them paid and cuts out
everybody like it's like you can't yes
$10 $15 month is an astronomical but
when you add them all up it is right
when you need all of these and they need
to work together and they're not gonna
work together cuz their game a or their
game beat like the meta project needs to
figure out how do you get them paid get
them to be sufficient well we're not for
that so that's the passion project 15
minutes
how we're gonna actually create this
thing right or have a next conversation
that's not during this time period for
moving this forward for having people be
able to know what we're doing and come
on board for a crazy Nepal well but what
about deciding okay we're gonna do a
chat around this and we're gonna create
a do Google Doc and either we use one of
the time slots for this or we create a
new one I mean we have people lined up
next week is James Jones cube spawn
while we're doing the financing the next
week is the education when I can
remember his name at Bowman sorry um and
I think that's all we have lined up at
the moment so I do have one other kind
of option for video chats and and it
uses zoom in the background but it's
called Kiko chat queue iqo chat com
I actually know the founder and he's
donated some space
well he's liked two different groups but
I don't know if he can afford to keep
doing that now he charges either a
members pay $3 a month which is kind of
still kind of a it's not a lot but you
know once you have to put your credit
card in something it's a bit challenging
or one cent per minute per person if he
if the central organization wants to pay
but it has a user zoom but it also has
built-in Doc's like for that meeting
there's a permanent doc in history and
so he's kind of built this as an online
discussion space so that might be
another option
yeah I'm pulling up here it looks very
interesting
qi qi o qi q o CH
at comm yeah I put a I put a link in the
private chat not a link I just put the
text it didn't turn into a link it was
having those tools er but I also feel
like 1 cent per minute like it's funny
because that was like long-distance
calls when they were 10 cents and it
were like nothing and now like it's free
why would why would we pay for but
having so if there's 10 people on the
call it's 10 cents a minute and we want
like a hundred people on the call so I
feel like if we're paying for it it
makes more sense for us to figure out a
Google Doc then for us to necessarily
have like have one common space it's
like here's the list of each Google Doc
for each week or each each one and cuz I
don't even know I like how to even
assess his software when we're not on it
right is it just a Google Doc and it
just formats it better because we have
to log in to be able to use it that's
two degrees away anyway
whereas with people that got one minute
per person that's that's just for the
video meeting everything else is free
mmm that's and that's because that's
what what zoom charges him he's just
passing on the costs yeah no I mean zoom
does has to have the free thing but
that's that's the the cost of using the
zoom video conferencing in the
background so all the other stuff the
documents and the searching and
everything should be built in I don't
think it does Auto transcribing but it
does have some community tools like a
hundred people on a zoom call which you
get for $15 a month would be 10 how many
someone do that math for me 100 cents
one dollar a dollar a minute right so
like sixty dollars for an hour which for
an organization isn't a lot but for a
non-profit starting out is like for
something that's that's game B and not
looking like why he gets charged two
cent per minute when he can't like why
is there not why can't he just use bunch
of free zoom accounts not free sorry $15
a month
well you can't do the integrations that
he has with it and some of the other
stuff and controlling it so he has yeah
it's just that's the way they charge it
but most people don't use it so you're
you're getting reduced costs because
there's a hundred people although the
have a zoom account and use it for a
couple meetings a month so yeah they're
just averaging the cost of our larger
group yeah so it might the way the
pricing works although I think if we'd
if the members if if everyone if the
mint we could get everyone to pay three
dollars a month then we could use it and
maybe that that could even be the start
of together tech it's like okay well the
first thing we're gonna do is we're
gonna instead of being $10 a month we're
going to start at $3 a month for this
but I don't know if it's worth it but
it's just an option it's got some
interesting features here some visual
problem mapping and yeah calendar a lot
of stuff check it out let's see I mean
it solves all of our problems and it's
$3 a month the other option is to
actually pay $10 a month
figure it out into a pool and then
payout that and then when people come
you don't I mean like it's kind of the
four of us with together tech at the
moment and even that week I just kind of
like include you onus NHL we haven't
actually like kind of called but like if
you'll put in ten dollars a month in and
we have enough space to invite people to
not pay right and then when they are
start getting actually involved it's
like by the way it's $10 a month to have
voting rights and to be part of the
maybe more more elite conversations to
be one of that I'd like tiered like you
do have more skin in the game when
you're actually paying into the
co-operative than when you're just
participating then I guess the point
where if we in order mean if we're
spending $3,000 a month on who coach at
then one we can see the metrics does it
make sense to just have it per one cent
per person and or
what's the point where we make our own
using zoom that you know it's cheaper to
make it than to pay someone else and
having that conversation with the
founder like this is cheaper how do we
integrate all of this together but again
whole other conversation we have 8
minutes left so yeah so do we want to go
ahead and create some text for how to
describe this and put it out there and
see people or I said who wants to do all
that work I'm willing to post it if if
someone else is going to type it up or
I'm also totally that with anyone else
posted yet sometimes I don't know
whether the algorithm is gonna be for me
because I post more or unfavorably
because I post more like way to people
to be what I put it for not I don't know
I can type out what we came up with here
and then we can decide and do we want to
just give a time like zoom account this
time who's interested and collect
information and send it out all the ones
that's also the Martin post it is people
that contact you to get the links to do
that right yeah I guess so worst case we
can all just have part three of this
discussion if no one else shows up right
I didn't say what went wrong yeah and I
don't know Edward if you want to you
could just start a Google Doc and share
it with us on the Facebook channel and
and then you could put down your text
and we can come in and make suggestions
if you want yeah let's let's start there
I think that's a good place to start
okay
join make a chat he's starting our fix
our world Friday chat with us so I can
either add him or we can just have
another group that's brainstorming
brainstorming or do you want to go ahead
and make one for this for the project
raising the issue with that I mean I
guess but then it's gonna go out to
everyone who's part of a project raising
right like people don't necessarily keep
coming back just because they have their
project raised or just a whole
conversation
we also hmm I feel like Project Racing
is gonna be very similar to what we're
doing it's just instead of people having
projects it's gonna be individual to the
project and how many times do you come
and raise someone else before you're
raised right like you know we need
people's ideas and butts in the seat to
be part of it and if you're only taking
or not giving what is what does that
look like
or do we care yeah if you don't mind to
just make a quick facebook chat group
and everyone can show the link yeah
that's alone yeah doesn't take much time
or much space right yeah it's just
getting started and doing something and
and you know taking it from there I'm
still calling a brainstorm that's it
like I have so many of these going to
the limit but actually it's I mean it's
much better than having one off ones and
I'm already part of it cuz I'm creating
it there we go I made it type - hello
just cuz I didn't know what else to type
in there and we can edit that and I
don't their pickup time do we want to do
to like not next Saturday or the
Saturday after but the Saturday after
that which that late like the 22nd after
that I'm not available on the weekend of
the 18th that one is cuz that's oh I'm
sorry I'm sorry wrong month on the
weekend of the 15th 15 yeah so that's
two weekends from now this is 30 weekend
announcements yeah I'm free on the 22nd
yeah who talked about the same time as
this meeting or yeah we can because
there's no one scheduled so instead of
having this week that's what happened
and we'll put up soon to generate to
generate buzz and generate maybe me even
create an event for it and then also put
something o much closer to the time
period as well because people don't
really think about things two weeks in
advance or 3 B it's really in advance
but also it's good some people do so
people need to change their schedule
around and will want to come to it and
that's the good thing about an event as
well as it actually reminds you yourself
right and it's just like posting assume
you want to go ahead and put an event in
the game B before this try that we can
do that once we get the text figure it
out so then people can have that
conversation too which is why an event
is also good because it creates that
conversation in there that's right and
then that like you probably need to
figure out with it what
the meeting actually looks like right is
it just coming and then breaking off
what are we breaking off and talking
about maybe having to be a little more
idea cafe where there's questions that
we the group everyone takes to turn to
share or just a topic that they talk
about for half an hour and then come
back together and break off into a new
group like actually structuring that
with okay I think it would be
interesting to see how many people show
up but if there's not a whole bunch of
people then it would just be going
through each person saying do they not
have a passion or do they have a passion
that they want help starting and then we
just focus on each person if there's a
lot of people then we break up into
groups and everyone has 15 minutes and
they do it for an hour you know
something yeah they come back together
and have a bigger conversation of like
what were your passion projects and and
we want to say come to this meeting
whether you you need help on a passion
project or if you're just willing to
help out
yeah right so there will be we'll need
to see how many people want help and
then they will need take it they could
probably each have their own group
depending on how many helpers there are
but yeah I think we could figure that
out what do we do if there's more than
100 not a problem that's fine well we'll
figure that out yes that would be an
awesome problem alright down with them
to Saturdays alright so we have 30 more
seconds should are we time should we say
goodbye to YouTube
I think we should yes a bye to YouTube
all right thanks for hanging out YouTube
see you next week for how to get a money